Infographics are a creative and communicative way to tell stories with data.
The core idea behind them is blending visual elements with charts to create a compelling narrative.
However, for non-design experts, designing from scratch is challenging.
Specifically, how to make the inserted chart style consistency and visual harmony with the overall design.
To achieve that, there are lots of design decisions should be made, such as which color palette to use.
How to arrange the layout? How can we keep elements consistent in style?
And we found all these answers can be solved by selecting a well-designed template as reference.
We propose chart tone.
Starting from a well-designed template, it binds chart elements, including text and data relevant components such as line elements,
with visual elements to achieve a seamless integration.
For example, let's import some data and create a bar chart about Safari animals.
Next, we drag a template image onto the canvas in the template frame.
The template is then decomposed into two parts, a background image and individual design elements.
Since the template doesn't contain visuals for Safari animals, we use a duck illustration as a reference.
With the style propagation function, we generate new elements, a zebra, a giraffe, and a lion.
These generated animals share the same artistic style and pose as the duck, ensuring consistency.
To blend them with the chart, we use the binding function.
Clicking the Binding button allows us to establish bidirectional connections between objects, specifying which two elements should be combined.
Or, to speed things up, we can group these frames and bind them to the entire chart.
Each frame will then automatically link to a bar element, bind them one by one, or group multiple bindings together for efficiency.
The generated animals are automatically aligned with the height of the original chart while preserving their visual style.
We can compose these visual elements on the background image and add decorations for extra detail.
Beyond visuals, we also support text visual binding, enabling the generation of stylized text that matches the overall design.
Users can browse the layout library for chart and template recommendations, and apply them to the canvas with a single click.
To make the final infographic even more polished, we can refine it with lighting and shadow effects.
Or animate the composition to add dynamic story chart tone.
We enable charts to seamlessly integrate into design templates, blending data, text, and visuals into infographics that tell a visual story about data.